A Guide to the Isaac Hammond Collection, 1839-1875
Library of Virginia
Library of Virginia
Isaac Hammond Collection, 1839-1875
Library of Virginia
24335
.45 cubic feet
Isaac Hammond
Administrative Information
Access Restrictions
There are no restrictions.
Acquisition Information
Gift of the Huguenot Historical Society, New Paltz, New York, 12 April 1955.
Biographical Information
Born about 1841, Isaac Hammond enlisted in Company F, 80th New York Infantry 17 December 1863. He, along with his regiment, was in Richmond in 1865. He gathered materials from the state and Confederate archives. Hammond took these items back to New York after his regiment was mustered out of the army 29 Janaury 1866 in Portsmouth, Virginia. After his death, the items were given to the Huguenot Historical Society in New Paltz, New York.
Scope and Content Information
Collection, 1839-1875, of Isaac Hammond of New York, a Union soldier who was stationed for a time in Richmond, Virginia, and gathered various documents from the files of Governors John Letcher and William Smith, the Virginia General Assembly, the Confederate Congress, the files of Confederate Senators James M. Baker of Florida and R. M. T. Hunter of Virginia, and the Confederate adjutant-general's office. The material covers a wide range of subjects including the impressment of slaves for working on Confederate and local defenses, hospitals, the plights of women and children in Virginia during the Civil War, military defenses, supplies for various companies in the Confederate army, pay vouchers, military passes, military orders, and newspapers from Richmond, Virginia, Montgomery, Alabama, and Augusta, Georgia.
Correspondents include John A. Campbell, Samuel P. Moore, Otho R. Singleton, Albert G. Brown, James M. Baker, Robert M. T. Hunter, Fitzhugh Lee, Samuel Cooper, James A. Seddon, H. L. Clay, Richard W. Walker, Robert Jemison, Jr., Robert Ranson, Jr., Braxton Bragg, Joseph Mayo, Joseph E. Johnston, Jeremy Francis Gilmer, George W. Munford, Jefferson Davis, Richard Stoddert Ewell, John Brown Gordon, James Lawson Kemper, Joseph R. Davis, Pierre G. T. Beauregard and William Hicks Jackson.
Arrangement
Arranged chronologically.
Contents List
- Stock certificate no. 1179, 14 November 1839, for $100 by the James River and Kanawha Company to Robert T. Lynch. Certificate authorized by act passed 23 March 1839., 2 p., printed form. (Folder 1)
- Account, January-June 1850, Leekey [or Lukey] Hutchinson with S. S. Gresham and Brothers, 1 leaf, Ms. (Folder 1)
- Address delivered by Governor Henry A. Wise before the Virginia Mechanics Institute of the city of Richmond, October 1856, Published by Ritchie and Dunnavant, Richmond., 15 p., printed. (Folder 1)
- Commission, 2 September 1857, adjutant with the rank of captain in the 1st Regiment of Virginia Volunteers, 2nd Brigade, 4th Division, Virginia Militia to William Munford from Governor Henry A. Wise., 1 leaf, printed form. (Folder 1)
- Broadside, 25 December 1856, carrier's address to the patrons of the "Richmond Enquirer.", 1 leaf, printed.
- Duty report, 1 November 1859, for Company E, Richmond Light Infantry Blues, Richmond, Virginia, by Fred. Carter, First Sergeant., 1 leaf, Ms. (Folder 1)
- Special order no. -, 22 December 1859, by William Munford, adjutant, 1st Regiment, Virginia Volunteers, Richmond, Virginia, for Lieutenant James Crenshaw of Company F. Crenshaw is detailed to serve on a garrison court-martial., 1 leaf, Ms. (Folder 1)
- Report of the James River and Kanawha Company in answer to a Resolution of the House of Delegates on the Subject of the Improvement, & C., 13 January 1860, Document No. 43 of the session of the Virginia General Assembly, 1859-1860., 48 p., printed. (Folder 1)
- Address of the Hon. C. G. Memminger, Special Commissioner from the State of South Carolina before the Assembled Authorities of the State of Virginia, 19 January 1860, document No. 58 of the session of the Virginia General Assembly, 1859-1860., 43 p., printed. (Folder 1)
- Stock certificate, 19 March 1860, No. 2811 for $100 to Jacob Lynch for purchase of state stock. Endorsement on back stating $100 paid to Samuel E. Goodson by office of the 2nd auditor., 2 p., printed form and endorsement on back. (Folder 1)
- Circular letter, 12 July 1860, John Letcher, Governor of Virginia, concerning Commissioners of Elections., 1 leaf, printed. (Folder 1)
- Commission, 20 September 1860, as major in the 1st Regiment of Virginia Volunteers, 2nd Brigade, 4th Division, to William Munford from Governor John Letcher., 1 leaf, printed form. (Folder 1)
- Regulations for the Commissary's Department of the State of Virginia, 1861, Published by Chas. H. Wynne, Printer, Richmond, Virginia. This is no. 2374 in Confederate Imprints., 38 p., printed. (Folder 2)
- Letter, 17 January 1861 [probably misdated, should be 1862], from Captain James Mulligan, Department of Norfolk, Virginia, to Governor John Letcher. Forwarding a letter from the enemy., 1 leaf, ALS. (Folder 2)
- Letter, 28 January 1861 [probably misdated, should be 1862], H. M. Price, Highland County, Virginia, to John Letcher, Governor of Virginia, offering to gather information on the movements of the enemy in western Virginia., 2 p., ALS. (Folder 2)
- Remarks of the Hon. Stephen A. Douglas in the Senate of the United States, March 6, 1861, on the Resolution of Mr. Dixon to Print the Inaugural Address of President Lincoln, 1861,., 7 p., printed. (Folder 2)
- Telegram, 15 March (1861?) [probably 1864], from Duff C. Green, Quartermaster General, [state of Alabama], Montgomery, Alabama, to R. W. Walker, Richmond, Virginia, concerning exporting cotton., 2 p., printed form and handwritten message. (Folder 2)
- Letter, 25 September 1861, Lieutenant Colonel M. G. Harman, Headquarters, Forces at Staunton, Virginia, C.S.A., to John Letcher, Governor of Virginia, asking for reinforcements., 2 leaves, ALS. (Folder 2)
- Twenty-sixth Annual Report of the President and Directors of the Virginia Central Railroad Company to the Stockholders, at Their Annual Meeting, November 1861, 1861, Published by K. K. Ellyson, Printer, Richmond, Virginia., 88 p. printed. (Folder 2)
- Letter, 5 November 1861, John Echols, Headquarters, 27th Virginia Regiment, Centreville, Virginia, to John Letcher, Governor of Virginia, concerning the appointment of John Tiffany as tax collection in Monroe County, (West) Virginia., 2 p., ALS., endorsement on back. (Folder 2)
- Letter, 20 November 1861, Major A. G. Reger and Lieutenant Colonel G. W. Hansbrough, Camp Barton to J. P. Benjamin, Acting Secretary of War., 3 p., ALS., including wrapper endorsement. (Folder 2)
- Resolution, 22 November 1861, passed in the Virginia Convention of 1861 regarding the protection of southwestern Virginia., 1 leaf, Ms. (Folder 2)
- Letter, 25 November 1861, from an unknown recipient to Governor John Letcher. This is a fragment of a letter from someone in the post office department of the Confederate States of America., 2 p., Ms. fragment. (Folder 2)
- Letter, 28 November 1861, from Major A. G. Reger, Summit of Alleghany, to John Brannon concerning a promotion to lieutenant colonel., 2 p., ALS. with endorsement. (Folder 2)
- Letter, [1861], William D. Nutt, Acting Treasurer, C.S.A., to Captain [Lafayette H.] Fitzhugh, Sergeant at Arms, Senate, C.S.A., regarding payment of members of the Senate and the House of Representatives., 1 leaf, ALS. (Folder 2)
- Speech of George W. Richardson of Hanover in the Committee of the Whole on the Report of the Committee on Federal Relations in the Convention of Virginia, April 4, 1861, 1862, Published by the Whig Book and Job Office, Richmond, Virginia, in 1862., 32 p., printed. (Folder 3)
- Letter, 4 January 1862, John H. Claiborne of Petersburg, Virginia, to Governor John Letcher, Governor of Virginia regarding his resignation as senator., 1 leaf, ALS. (Folder 3)
- Letter, 11 January 1862, Elizabeth Rogers to Governor John Letcher asking that her son be given leave during the cold weather months. Also includes endorsements, including a rejection by Stonewall Jackson., 4 p., ALS., and endorsements. (Folder 3)
- Power of attorney, 17 February 1862, from Ruffin Acree and George Norman, free Negroes to Benjamin F. Gresham, all of King and Queen County, Virginia, for Gresham to sign receipts and receive payments due to Acree and Norman., 1 leaf, Ms.. (Folder 3)
- Order, 14 March 1862, to superintendent of Richmond and Petersburg Railroad by Captain D. H. Wood, Quartermaster's Department, C.S.A., Richmond, Virginia, that transportation be furnished for four boxes belonging to L. H. Fitzhugh, Thomasville, North Carolina., 1 leaf, printed form filled in. (Folder 3)
- Letter, 12 May 1862,S. R. Anderson, Richmond, to C. G. Meminger, treasurer [Secretary of the Treasury], concerning an individual interested in a position in the Treasury Department., 1 leaf, ALS. (Folder 3)
- Request, 15 November 1862, by L. S. Rayfield for 300 loaves of bread for Chimborazo Hospital No. 4, Richmond., 1 leaf, Ms. (Folder 3)
- Invoice, 10 December 1862, Quartermaster stores turned over at Winchester, Virginia, by Major S. M. Yost, Quartermaster, C.S.A., to Major George H. Kyle, C.S., and A.Q.M., 1 leaf, printed form filled in. (Folder 3)
- Receipt, 12 December 1862, articles received at Winchester by Captain John E. Howard, A.Q.M., C. S. A., from Quartermaster's Department on 30 November, 10 December and 12 December 1862., 1 leaf, printed form filled in. (Folder 3)
- Letter, 29 December 1862,J. A. Campbell, Assistant Secretary of War, C.S.A., Richmond, to James M. Baker, Lake City, Florida, concerning Baker's letter for troops for home defense., 1 leaf, ALS. (Folder 3)
- Abstract, 31 December 1862, articles expended, lost, destroyed in public service at Strasburg, Virginia, in the quarter ending 31 December 1862 by Major George H. Kyle, C.S. and A.Q.M., 1 leaf, printed form filled in.
- Receipt, 31 December 1862, articles received at New Market, Virginia, by Charles W. Hodges, acting ordnance Officer, Maryland troops, from Quartermaster's Department, C.S.A., 1 leaf, printed form filled in. (Folder 3)
- Roll, 1862, Captain David M. Lea's "Governor's Mounted Guard," 4th Virginia Cavalry., 2 p., Ms. (Folder 3)
- Letter, 10 January 1863,S. P. Moore, Surgeon General C.S.A., Richmond, to Alexander H. Stevens, Vice President, C.S.A., Richmond, regarding smallpox vaccinations for the Senate., 1 leaf, ALS. (Folder 4)
- Letter, 13 January 1863, Raleigh W. Dyer, Henry County, Virginia, to [R. M. T.?] Hunter regarding a petition on the conditions in the Confederacy., 4 p., ALS. (Folder 4)
- Receipt, 31 January 1863, issued to Henry Wilkinson by Treasury Department, C.S.A., for services as laborer. Noted as paid., 1 leaf, Ms. (Folder 4)
- Receipt, 6 February 1863, wood adn coal received in Richmond by Captain T. B. Starke, 25th Virginia Battalion, from Quartermaster's Department, C.S.A., 1 leaf, printed form filled in. (Folder 4)
- Special requisition, 17 February 1863, articles of clothing for Captain L. B. McMullan, Company D, 4th Regiment of Virginia Heavy Artillery., 2 p., printed form filled in. (Folder 4)
- receipt, 25 February 1863, glass tumbler received by Comptroller's Office, C.S.A., from T. A. Jacobs. Noted as paid, but no date given., 1 leaf, Ms. (Folder 4)
- Receipt, 2 March 1863, soap received by Treasury Department, C.S.A., from E. W. Tompkins 13 December 1862. Noted as paid 2 March 1863., 1 leaf, Ms. (Folder 4)
- Letter, 3 March 1863,S. P. Moore, Surgeon General, C.S.A., Richmond, to James M. Baker, Richmond, regarding Reverend William K. Kennedy as a chaplain for the Florida hospital.., 1 leaf, ALS. (Folder 4)
- Letter, 11 March 1863, Aug. H. Fonte, Jackson, [Mississippi], to A. G. Brown, letter of introduction for Major Gregory., 1 leaf, ALS. (Folder 4)
- Interrogatories form, 22 April 1863, filled in by John W. Paulett, Wythe County, Virginia, filled in order to obtain a merchant's license., 2 p., form filled in. (Folder 4)
- Letter, 24 June 1863, W. H. S. Taylor, Auditor, C.S.A., by T. Calvert, to Hosea Balderree, Magnolia, Columbus County, Arkansas, sending certificate for pay of Private J. Baldwin., 1 leaf, ALS. (Folder 4)
- Estimate, 30 June 1863, of expenses of the House of Representatives of the Confederate States of America from 1 February 1863 to 30 June 1863., 1 leaf, Ms. (Folder 4)
- Pay voucher, 2 p., form filled in. (Folder 4)
- Medical certificate, 10 November 1863, Private James Latham, Company I, 21st Mississippi Infantry, found incapable of performing duties of a soldier, by A. I. Semmes, Senior Surgeon for Examining Board., 2 p., form filled in. (Folder 4)
- Passport, 7 December 1863, issued to C. B. Mitchell, [Confederate States Senate], by Major E. Griswold, Provost Marshall [C.S.A.], Richmond., 1 leaf, form filled in. (Folder 4)
- Receipt, 7 December 1863, shoe pegs received in Richmond by Major John C. Maynard, from Quartermaster's Department, C.S.A., 2 p., form filled in. (Folder 4)
- Tally sheet, 7 December 1863, for the Confederate States Senate, third session of the first Congress commencing 7 December 1863. Sheet is unused., 1 leaf, printed form (Folder 4)
- Letter, 14 December 1863, Singleton, Confederate States House of Representatives, to A. G. Brown, Confederate States Senate, requesting the signature of Brown and others apparently in an effort to secure a government post for someone., 1 leaf, ALS. (Folder 4)
- Letter, 20 December 1863, from an unknown correspondent to an unknown recipient concerning the war., 14 p., Ms. (Folder 4)
- A Discourse before the General Assembly of South Carolina, on December 10, 1863, Appointed by the Legislature as a Day of Fasting, Humiliation, and Prayer. by B. M. Palmer, D.D., of New Orleans, La., 1864, published by Charles P. Pelham, state printer, Columbia, South Carolina., 24 p., printed. (Folder 5)
- An Act for the Relief Families of Soldiers and Sailors from Virginia, within the Lines of the Enemy, and Regulations for the Government of Agents in Distributing the Fund, 1864, No. 2267 in Confederate Imprints., 7 p., printed. (Folder 5)
- Broadside, [1864], Standing Committees of the Senate, Second Congress. No. 232 in Confederate Imprints., 1 leaf, printed. (Folder 5)
- Journal of the House of Delegates of the State of Virginia for the Called Session of 1864, 1864, published by William F. Ritchie, Public Printer, Richmond. No. 2363 in Confederate Imprints., 48 p., printed. (Folder 5)
- Journal of the Senate of the Commonwealth of Virginia: Begun and Held at the Capitol, in the City of Richmond, on Wednesday, the Seventh Day of December, in teh Year One THousand Eight Hundred and Sixty-Four--Being the Eighty-Eighth of the Commonwealth. Extra Session, 1864, published by James E. Goode, Senate Printer. No. 2299 in Confederate Imprints., 8 p. printed, incomplete. (Folder 5)
- Map, 1864, field of war around Richmond and Petersburg by Andrew B. Cross, Baltimore, [Maryland]., 1 leaf, printed. (Folder 5)
- Message of the Governor of Virginia and Accompanying Documents, 1864, Document I of the Session of the Virginia General Assembly, 1864-1865. Included are also corrections in the governor's message, Document XVI. Published by William F. Ritchie, Public Printer. No. 2283 in Confederate Imprints., 22 p. and 4 p., printed. (Folder 5)
- Letter, 3 January 1864, John [T.?] Gilchrist, Lake City, [Florida], to James M. Baker, Confederate States Senate, concerning the war in Florida and slavery., 3 p., ALS. (Folder 6)
- Letter, 5 January 1864, D. S. [or G.] Walker, Tallahassee, [Florida], to James M. Baker, Richmond, containing personal news and thoughts on the war., 3 p., ALS. (Folder 6)
- Memorial of the Railraod Companies on the Exemption Law, 16 January 1864, to the Senate and House of Representatives of the Confederate States of America. No. 1171 in Confederate Imprints., 1 leaf, printed. (Folder 6)
- Letter, 17 January 1864, J. W. McMurran of Fauquier County, Virginia, to Governor William Smith concerning the war., 4 p., ALS. (Folder 6)
- Letter, 23 January 1864, B. W. Arnold, adjutant, 14th Virginia Infantry, Kinston, North Carolina, to R. M. T. Hunter, Senator from Virginia, regarding the act for payment of adjutants., 1 leaf, ALS. (Folder 6)
- Letter, 3 February 1864, F. Livingston, Madison, Florida, to James M. Baker concerning impressment, cost of provisions, and other war-related matters., 1 leaf, ALS. (Folder 7)
- Letter, 17 February 1864,Fitz Lee, Major General, C.S.A., Orange Court House, [Virginia], to Colonel R. H. Chilton, Chief of Staff, Army of Northern Virginia, concerning citizens' complaints about expeditions into Hardy and Hampshire Counties, (West) Virginia., 6 p., ALS. with endorsements. (Folder 7)
- Proclamation and General Orders 64, 18 February 1864, consisting of proclamation of pardon by Abraham Lincoln, President of the United States 8 December 1864 and copy of General Orders no. 64. from the War Department regarding refugees and deserters from the rebel army., 5 p., printed. (Folder 7)
- Broadside, 22 February 1864, listing Senators of the Confederate States of America [in the First Congress] from 22 February 1862 to February 1864. No. 95[?] in More Confederate Imprints., 1 leaf, printed. (Folder 7)
- Broadside, April 1864, substance of the speech delivered by John H. Gilmer before Judge J. B. Halyburton, in the District Court, on the Act of Congress Suspending the Privileges of the Writ of Habeas Corpus. No. 2755 in Confederate Imprints., 1 leaf, printed.
- Letter, 7 April 1864, O. J. E. Stuart, Lowndes County, Alabama, to A. G. Brown, Macon, Georgia, concerning Edward Stuart and his injured leg., 2 p., ALS. (Folder 8)
- Note, 7 April 1864, from T. B. Gates requesting that the bearer be given a copy of printed General Orders [No. 17], Army of the Potomac., 1 leaf, Ms. (Folder 8)
- Letter, 21 April 1864, Anne Murphey to her husband John Murphey containing family news and expressing concern over John. Letter was found at the Wilderness after the battle there in May 1864., 4 p., AMs. (Folder 8)
- Letter, 29 April 1864, Colonel J. B. Terrill, 13th Virginia Infantry, to S. Cooper, Adjutant and Inspector General, C.S.A., concerning the promotion of Lieutenant S. D. Buck to captain., 2 p., ALS. includes endorsements. (Folder 8)
- Tally sheet, 2 May 1864, for the Confederate States Senate, First Session, Second Congress, commencing 2 May 1864. Sheet is unused., 1 leaf, printed. (Folder 9)
- Letter, 4 May 1864, Captain J. T. Bemaree[?], 8th Florida Regiment, to James M. Baker asking for help in getting new clothes for his regiment., 1 leaf, ALS. (Folder 9)
- Letter, 4 May 1864, James A. Seddon, Secretary of War, C.S.A., to Governor William Smith of Virginia concerning the quickly organized troop of men to defend Richmond., 2 p., ALS. (Folder 9)
- Note, 6 May 1864, from Private John A. Beaty concerning his efforts to transfer from Company F, 3rd Alabama Infantry to Company B, 17th Virginia Infantry. Contains request and supporting documents, including endorsements., 3 leaves, and 2 p., Ms. (Folder 9)
- Letter, 21 May 1864, Captain L. W. Richardson, Commandant, Eastern District Military Prison [Castle Thunder], Richmond, to Governor William Smith regarding the rations for prisoners held there., 1 leaf, ALS. (Folder 9)
- Letter, 21 May 1864, Captain William E. Warren, Quartermaster's Office, C.S.A., Richmond, to Mr. Goddin concerning the rent of buildings in Richmond., 1 leaf, ALS. (Folder 9)
- Letter, 23 May 1864, H. L. Clay, Adjutant and Inspector General's Office, Richmond, to Senators Walker and Jemison regarding Colonel E. A. O'Neal., 1 leaf, ALS. (Folder 9)
- Letter, 25 May 1864,R. Ranson, Major General, C.S.A., Richmond, to Governor [William] Smith concering troops under Ranson's command in Richmond., 1 leaf, ALS. (Folder 9)
- Letter, 30 May 1864, Colonel J. B. Danforth to Governor [William] Smith concerning troops for the defense of Richmond and shoes and clothes for them., 1 leaf, ALS. (Folder 9)
- Invoice, 31 May 1864, subsistence stores delivered at Richmond by Captain F. F. Myer, A.C.S., C.S.A. to Captain E. T. Ferrell, A.C.S., C.S.A., 1 leaf, form filled in. (Folder 9)
- Letter, June 1864, Braxton Bragg, Major General, C.S.A., to William Smith, Governor of Virginia, regarding the militia called out by the President., 1 leaf, ALS. (Folder 10)
- Letter, June 1864, Joseph Mayo, Mayor of the city of Richmond, to William Smith, Governor of Virginia, concerning "insubordination" among the black population of the city., 2 p., ALS. (Folder 10)
- Letter, 4 June 1864, S. L. Neblack, Lake City, [Florida], to Baker informing him of Union incursions and fighting in Florida., 4 p., ALS. (Folder 10)
- Extract, 8 June 1864, of Special Orders No. 133 ordering Captain James B. Parramore to report to General Robert E. Lee for reassignment, from Adjutant and Inspector General's Office, Richmond, by command of the Secretary of War, by John Withers, Assistant Adjutant General., 1 leaf, printed form filled in. (Folder 10)
- Letter, 14 June 1864,J. A. Campbell, Assistant Secretary of War, C.S.A., Richmond, to A. G. Brown, Confederate States Senate, regarding the resignation of Lieutenant Colonel James B. McRae., 1 leaf, ALS. (Folder 10)
- Pass, 26 June 1864, issued by Colnel S. Crutchfield, Headquarters, ARtillery, Third Corps, Army of Northern Virginia, for his "servant boy" George Bibey for a round trip from Petersburg, [Virginia], to Richmond and back., 1 leaf, Ms. (Folder 10)
- Register of the Officers and Cadets of the Virginia Military Institute, Lexington, Va., July 1864, published by Macfarlane & Fergusson, Printers, Richmond, Virginia. No. 4020 in Confederate Imprints., 39 p., printed. (Folder 11)
- Letter, 15 July 1864, J. E. Mosby, Jr., to "Phil" asking if he would apply to the Governor to allow Mosby to draw flour from the state's stores., 1 leaf, ALS. (Folder 11)
- Abstracts of dispatches, 16 July 1864, Joseph Johnston, General, C.S.A. to General Braxton Bragg and President Jefferson Davis detailing military actions of his army in Georgia from 27 Jun to 16 July 1864. Also includes a copy of the official returns from Johnston's army 10 July 1864., 3 p., Ms. (Folder 11)
- Exemption certificate, 23 July 1864, from the Board of Examiniation exempting James T. Pace of Richmond County, Georgia, from military service., 1 leaf, Ms., copy. (Folder 11)
- Admittance form, 30 July 1864, Private Michael H. Wells, Company C, 9th Virginia Infantry, admitting him into Chimborazo Hospital, [Richmond]., 1 leaf, form filled in. (Folder 11)
- Receipt, 23 August 1864, for Pants received by Major William G. Bentley from Captain James F. West, Quartermaster's Department, C.S.A., Richmond., 1 leaf, form filled in. (Folder 12)
- Exemption certificate, 10 September 1864, from Lieutentant James H. Binford, Conscript Office, Richmond, exempting Robert Healy, Jr., Justice of the Peace, Middlesex County, [Virginia], from military service., 2 p., form filled in and endorsements on back. (Folder 13)
- Letter, 24 September 1864, James Shuter, Acting President, Southern Express Company, Augusta, Georgia, to J. F. Gibson, Richmond, sending the company's rates (not included)., 1 leaf, ALS. (Folder 13)
- Letter, 24 September 1864, R. D. Ward, Richmond, to Governor [William] Smith concerning the case of Ann Edwards and her arrest in Culpeper County, [Virginia], early in the war, and her subsequent release and order to stay in Richmond. Also includes a note from the War Department, 3 p., ALS., with endorsements. (Folder 13)
- Diet roll, 29 September 1864, for Ward K, 3rd Division, Chimborazo Hospital., 1 leaf, form filled in. (Folder 13)
- Letter, 29 September 1864, H. A. Hamilton, Agent for Southern Express Company, Richmond, to Governor William Smith regarding the company's shipping costs., 2 leaves, ALS. (Folder 13)